mobshare.in 2008-12-19

# Mobshare.in Blog » Privacy Policy

#### 1\. MOBME PRIVACY POLICY

mobME is committed to respecting the privacy of its customers’ information. As a part of your use of our websites and/or receipt of certain mobME products and services you may share some personal data with us. This Privacy Policy describes how we will handle personal data that you share with us. Throughout this Privacy Policy “personal data” means information relating to an identified or identifiable individual (i.e., a natural person).

We wish to inform you of the types of personal data we collect and store, the purposes for which that personal data will be processed, in what circumstances that personal data may be shared with third parties and/or transferred to other countries, the security measures we take to protect personal data, your rights as a data subject and how to exercise your rights.

We recommend that you take a few minutes to familiarize yourself with the provisions of this Privacy Policy.

By using a mobME website or product or service to which this Privacy Policy applies _you express your agreement to the processing of your personal data_ in the manner provided in this Privacy Policy.

#### 2\. MOBME PRODUCTS AND SERVICES TO WHICH THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLIES

_Online_  
This Privacy Policy applies to the processing of all personal data collected by mobME Wireless Solutions Private Limited or its wholly owned Affiliates (together referred to as “mobME”, “we” or “our”) through the use of a website controlled by mobME where a link or other reference to this Privacy Policy is made (see, for example, _[www.mobme.in](http://www.mobme.in/)_ ).

Furthermore this Privacy Policy applies to the processing of personal data collected in connection with mobME providing products and/or services to you on-line, unless otherwise stated in the terms and conditions applicable to a particular product and service.

_Offline_  
This Privacy Policy also applies in the offline environment in relation to personal data collected in connection with the promotion, sale, offering and/or provision of mobME products and services.

Please note, that certain mobME products and/or services may have a specific privacy policy of their own that will apply. This will usually be indicated in the terms and conditions or other material for the product or service concerned. Where that is the case the specific privacy policy for that product or service will prevail over this Privacy Policy to the extent of any conflict in content.

Please also note that in connection with offering of certain mobME products and/or services, additional information regarding the use of personal data may be provided in the terms and conditions or other such material in relation to that product and service.

#### 3\. THE DATA WE COLLECT

mobME may collect personal data of various categories when you visit a mobME website or in connection with your use of mobME products and/or services. Examples of the categories of personal data mobME collects, for example, in connection with registering for a mobME service, ordering a mobME product or service, or participating in a sales promotion are set out below.

mobME will endeavour to collect only personal data which is necessary for the purpose for which it is being collected and to store such data for no longer than is necessary for carrying out such purpose(s).

**Your use of mobME websites**  
For the most part you may visit a mobME website without having to tell us who you are. Please note, however, that your web browser will generally provide us with certain information, such as IP-addresses, languages, access times, details of the website you linked from, information about the devices used in the communication (eg: your mobile phone serial number and model, your telephone number and other similar information). We use such technical information to keep track of the webpages you are visiting from, the links you use, the ad banners and other similar content you viewed along with other actions you may have taken on our website. Please also see the section on “The use of cookies”, below.

**Your registration and signing into mobME services**  
To register for certain mobME services, we may ask you to provide us with personal data, such as your name, street address, email address, telephone number, and other contact information. We may also ask you to indicate your preferences on how you wish us to communicate with you (eg: by email, SMS, etc.).

During registration for some services, we may also ask you to provide information such as your age, gender, postal code and other such demographic information, as well as information about your mobile devices and other devices, as well as other products and/or services you use.

Once you have registered, mobME may authorize you to access information and materials using the personal credentials either provided by you or created by mobME (or a third party on its behalf). Such credentials may include, for example, your email address and a password, or they may be based on Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) based certificates, banking or credit card information and other similar means we may use to authenticate registered users and to validate their actions. We store such information to the extent necessary for carrying out the tasks in question.

**The provision and use of mobME products and services online and offline**  
When you request and/or use mobME products and/or services online, certain technical information may be transmitted to us, such as details relating to the devices used and IP-addresses by which the communication took place.

We may also collect other information in connection with a particular product and/or service, including details of the requests you have made, the products and services provided (including their delivery details), details of agreements between mobME and you relating to the product and/or service, records of contact and communications between you and mobME and other such information as is created or collected in the course of offering and providing mobME products and services.

Certain mobME websites and/or services may enable you to upload or otherwise provide content and or other material to mobME websites. If you provide us with any such content or material, we may retain information relating to its provision such as details of the content you provided, your IP-address and other technical information created in the course of your that communication with us.

**Memberships in mobME’s loyalty programs and user communities**  
Insofar as you are a member of a mobME loyalty program or a user community, information related to your memberships and activities thereto may be collected.

**Your consents, feedback preferences, opinions and other information provided by you**  
The provision of some mobME services may require your explicit consent, such as certain direct marketing via electronic communications and certain services based on the use of your location data. In order to comply with your request to receive (or not receive) particular services, we retain details of the permissions you have provided.

We may ask you to provide us with feedback and opinions concerning our products and services and other activities. You may also be asked to provide us with information about your preferences, such as your interests.

Certain of mobME’s services may allow you personally to manage your profile, for example your consents, prohibitions and preferences.

**Payment and other financial information**  
Insofar as you decide to purchase some mobME products or services we may require you to provide us with certain financial information in order to complete the transaction. Such information may include, for example, credit card details, billing address and other such information that is needed to complete your request.

**Personal details of potential customers**  
You may have provided us with certain personal details, such as contact details, in relation to your interest in purchasing or using our products and services without you having an existing customer relationship with mobME. You may provide us with such information, for example, by participating in one of our sales promotions or competitions or by requesting information about our products and services. By providing us with your personal data you agree that you consent to us processing personal data for the purpose(s) for which it was provided.

We may also obtain some personal data from third parties, such as list-rental companies and other such publicly available sources, in order to contact you. When collecting personal data not provided by you for direct marketing purposes, we retain personal data only to the extent permitted by law.

**Other information created and stored by mobME**  
In order to be able to personalise our offerings to you and to create more attractive products and services, we may combine the information and personal data described above. We may also use the above information to create statistical information.

#### 4\. The Purposes for which we process your personal data

mobME processes the personal data and other information described above only in connection with the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

**Provision of products and/or services**  
In order to provide you with the products and/or services you have requested, the processing of your personal data may be needed. In case we need to invoice you for those products and services, your personal data will be used also for that purpose. Also, to help us fulfill your request, we may share information with others, for instance, other parts of mobME, mobME’s business partners, financial institutions, shipping companies, postal or government authorities (for example, Customs authorities) involved in the provision of a product or service. Personal data is also used to manage mobME’s accounts and records.

**Development and improvement of products and services**  
mobME strives continuously to improve and develop its products and services, as well as to create new ones, the better to meet our customer’s requirements. Sometimes it is necessary to use your personal data for that purpose.

**Communicating with you**  
We may use your personal data to communicate with you. We may, for example, wish to contact you in order to conduct market research, to inform you about our products and services or changes therein as well as to send you such information as we may be required to send. Certain mobME services provide you with the possibility to manage your preferences in terms of how you want us to communicate with you. Your personal data will also be processed in connection with your communication with us.

**Marketing of products and services**  
Your personal data may be used also to market our products and services to you as well as to do market research.  Before we use it in that way, however, we will offer you the opportunity to provide your consent to our doing so.  Also, some of our websites and other services we provide may be used for marketing products and services of companies with which mobME has agreed to such usage. However, mobME does not disclose your personal data to such companies or any other company for marketing purposes without your prior consent.

**Personalising our offering**  
We want to provide you with such an offering that would meet your personal demands. Therefore we may process your personal data in order to personalize our products and services to you. That may include, for example, customizing our websites and other services by obtaining and combining information relating to your use of other mobME’s products and services.

**Statistical purposes**  
We may also use your personal data for statistical purposes.

#### 5\. collecting the data of children

Generally, mobME avoids collecting the personal data of children. However, our databases may nevertheless contain personal data of children due to the fact that it is not always possible to determine precisely the age of the user. Insofar as we ask you to provide your age, we block the service from any person who is under 13 years of age. From time to time, we will also make reasonable efforts to clear our databases of personal data relating to children.

mobME’s policy is to request that minors (the age of minors is determined by local law where you reside) do not make purchases or engage in other legal acts on this site without the consent of a parent or legal guardian, unless otherwise permitted by applicable local law.

#### 6\. Ensuring data quality

We aim to keep the personal data accurate and up-to-date and to delete out of date or otherwise incorrect personal data.

Insofar as you provide us with your personal data directly, we would like to remind you that it is your responsibility to provide us with correct and relevant information. As certain mobME products and services may allow you to manage your profile, we also encourage you from time to time to access your details to ensure that your personal data is correct and up-to-date.

To the extent permitted by applicable legislation, we may use public sources in order to verify that personal data we possess is correct.

#### 7\. Regular disclosures and transfer of personal data

Generally, we do not sell, lease, rent or otherwise disclose your personal data to unauthorized third parties without your prior consent.

**mobME Affiliates,  processors and other involved parties**  
We may transfer and/or disclose your personal data between mobME Affiliates in connection with processing personal data for purpose(s) for which it was collected, being a purpose outlined in this Privacy Policy.

Generally, mobME may make use of third parties to process personal data on its behalf.  Personal data may also be transferred to mobME’s business partners to the extent necessary for the provision of our products and services, such parties being, for example, mobME’s professional advisers and mobME’s retailers selling or providing our products and services.  In all cases where a third party is granted access to personal data in order to provide processing services or as is necessary to provide mobME’s products and services, the third party is bound by contractual agreement to process your personal data consistently with this Privacy Policy and to  use appropriate security measures to protect the confidentiality and integrity of your personal data.

In case a part of mobME’s business is sold to a third party, the customer data registers relating to that business may be transferred to the entity that continues to operate the business.

_Financial and other such institutions_  
In relation to products and services requiring financial payment, your personal data may be provided to financial institutions and other third parties involved in such monetary transactions and in securing mobME’s financial interests related to that transaction.

**Law enforcement and other governmental bodies**

Certain law enforcement agencies and other governmental bodies may have a legal right to obtain personal data from mobME. In such a case, mobME transfers personal data to the extent required by law.

_International transfers_

mobME is a global organization having Affiliates, business processes, management structures, and technical systems that cross borders. This being the case, our products and/or services may be provided by using resources located in various countries around the world. Accordingly, your personal data may be transferred outside the country where you use the service or otherwise provide us with your personal data. That includes countries that do not have laws which provide specific protection for personal data where you may have fewer legal rights.  However, mobME’s privacy practices have been implemented so that all processing of your personal data is conducted in accordance with this Privacy Policy in every country where mobME does business.

#### 8\. How we protect your personal data against unauthorized or unlawful processing and against accidental loss or destruction of, or damage to, personal data

While there are always risks associated with providing personal data, whether in person, by phone or via the internet or other technologies, and no system of technology is completely safe or “tamper”/”hacker” proof, mobME endeavours to use appropriate measures (having regard to the nature of the personal data involved) to prevent and minimise such risks in connection with your use of our products and services.

We endeavour to take appropriate measures, such as the use of firewalls, secure server facilities, encryption, implementing of proper access rights management systems and processes, careful selection of processors and other technically and commercially reasonable measures to provide appropriate protection for your personal data against unauthorised use or disclosure. We also make appropriate back-up copies and use other such means to prevent the accidental damage or destruction to your personal data and to ensure that our services are functioning properly.

mobME uses encryption technology when collecting certain financial personal data such as credit card information. If a particular part of a mobME website supports on-line transactions, we will use an industry standard security measure, such as the one available through “Secure Sockets Layer” (” **SSL** “), to protect the confidentiality and security of online transactions.

#### 9\. Use of Cookies

From time to time when you visit a mobME website, information may be placed on your computer to allow us to recognize you. This information is commonly in the form of a textfile known as “cookie”. Cookies are small pieces of data stored on your computer’s hard drive, rather than on this website. Typically, they enable collection of certain information about your computer, including your internet protocol (IP) address, your computer’s operating system, your browser type and the address of any referring sites.

The use of cookies can provide benefits to you, such as eliminating the need for you to enter your password frequently during a session, or, where applicable, the need to re-enter items you place in a shopping cart if you do not finish a transaction in a single visit. Also, by showing us how and when our visitors use this site or other mobME sites, the use of cookies allows mobME to continue to improve the sites.

If you do not wish to receive cookies, or want to be notified before they are placed, you may set your web browser to do so, if your browser so permits. Please understand that if cookies are turned off or removed,, you may not be able to view certain parts of this site that may enhance your visit. Some of our business partners whose content is linked to or from this site may also use cookies. However, we have no access to or control over those cookies. This site also makes use of cookies for website traffic analysis and anonymous demographic profiling.

#### 10\. Electronic Direct marketing and the use your location data

We do not use your personal data to send you direct marketing by use of automated calling systems or by transmitting direct marketing to you by use of electronic communications, such as email, sms, mms or such messages, nor do we use your location data for any purpose unless you have explicitly given your prior consent to it by opting in. Your consent for such action will be asked per such a service.

#### 11\. Your rights as a INDIVIDUAL

As an individual about whom mobME processes personal data, you have the right.

  0. to obtain confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning you exists in mobME systems and communication of such data in understandable form;
  1. to obtain updating, rectification or, if relevant, integration of the data;

  2. to obtain the erasure, anonymization or blocking of data that have been processed unlawfully;

  3. to object, in whole or in part, on legitimate grounds, to the processing of personal data – in some cases, however, that may also mean the termination of the service or services provided by us to you;

  4. to object to the processing of personal data, where it is carried out for the purpose of sending advertising materials or direct selling or else for the performance of market or commercial communication surveys.

You may exercise your rights by contacting us through the contact points described in section 12 of this Privacy Policy.

#### 12\. the controller of your personal data and our contact details

mobME Wireless Solutions Private Limited, 41/3197, 4th Floor Bhageeratha Square, Bannerji Road, Cochin North, Kerala, India – 682018, shall be the controller of your personal data.

You may contact us by contacting the above contact points or by using contact information provided in mobME websites.

#### 13\. Changes to this privacy policy

mobME may from time to time change this Privacy Policy or change, modify or withdraw access to this site at any time with or without notice. However, if this Privacy Policy is changed in a material, adverse way, mobME will post a notice advising of such change at the beginning of this Policy and on this site’s home page for approximately 30 days. We recommend that you re-visit this Privacy Policy from time to time to learn of any such changes to this Privacy Policy.

Copyright © mobME Wireless Solutions Private Limited 2008. All rights reserved.
